* Company

Privacy Policy
==============

This Privacy Policy applies to Certo Software’s websites and software applications. Certo Software knows that you care how information about you is used and shared. This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by Certo Software when you access our websites or use our software, how the information will be used, and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources. The use of information collected through our websites and software shall be limited to the purposes under this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service to customers.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to a newsletter, fill out a form or use our software products.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, credit card information, IP address or other details to help you with your experience.

When using our software products we may collect non-personal usage data such as device operating system, device type and scan results to improve our products and offer better customer support.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, use our software or use certain other site features in the following ways:

* To personalize user’s experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
* To improve our website in order to better serve you.
* To improve our products and services.
* To prevent spam, fraud or abuse of our website and our services.
* To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.
* To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.
* To quickly process your transactions.

**How long do we keep your data?**

If you are a customer of Certo Software, we will retain your information for as long as your subscription is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

If you are a visitor to Certo Software’s websites we will retain your information for as long as necessary but no longer than five years after your last visit to our websites.

**How do we protect your information?**

We do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order, enters, submits, or accesses their information, to maintain the safety of your personal information.

All transactions are processed through a third party payment processor and are not stored or processed on our servers. These third parties are properly regulated and authorized to handle your payment information and are prohibited from using your personal data for promotional purposes or for any other purposes other than providing these services to us.

**Do we use ‘cookies’?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

We use cookies to:

* Help remember and process the items in the shopping cart.
* Understand and save user’s preferences for future visits.
* Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies, some of our services will not function properly.

**Third Party Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Third party links**

We do not include or offer third party products or services on our website.

**Your rights with respect to your data**

You have the right to ask us about the personal data we process about you, the purpose and nature of the processing, and to provide information on who we share it with. You have the right to request that we update, correct, delete (assuming that this does not impact the services we are providing to you) or export your data, as well as the right to object to processing and lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority. You can exercise these rights by emailing us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.certosoftware.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Please note that we may reject or refuse to fulfil to the fullest extent requests which risk the privacy of others or are unreasonable or repetitive, or would require disproportionate effort.

You have the right to opt-out of receiving certain emails (e.g., marketing communications) at any time by following the relevant unsubscribe process outlined in the applicable email. Please be aware that our emails may include important or useful information about our services. We may also contact you via email in the context of our contract (transaction) to give you information about the transaction or the term of your license. Given the transactional nature of these emails, these are necessary in order for us to manage our relationship with you and may not be able to unsubscribe from these transactional emails.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:  
Users can visit our site anonymously  
Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.  
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:

* On our Privacy Policy Page

Users are able to change their personal information:

* By emailing us

**How does our site handle do not track signals?**  
We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?**  
It’s also important to note that we allow third party behavioral tracking

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:

We will notify the users via email

* Within 7 business days

We will notify the users via in site notification

* Within 7 business days

We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us and we will promptly remove you from **ALL** correspondence.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

[\[email protected\]](https://www.certosoftware.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Last Edited on 2022-10-24

Scan. Detect. Remove.

Copyright © 2024 Certo Software Limited | Registered in England & Wales No. 10072356

Designed & developed by [Bigger Picture](https://biggerpicture.agency/ "Bigger Picture")

Certo

Sign up to our newsletter
-------------------------

Receive the latest mobile security news, exclusive discounts & offers straight to your inbox!

 Submit

Apple, the Apple logo, and iPhone are trademarks of Apple Inc., registered in the U.S. and other countries. App Store is a service mark of Apple Inc. Android, Google Play and the Google Play logo are trademarks of Google LLC.
